[Music]
[音乐]
hi there my name is Adam arise I work at
您好，我叫亚当，我在
Oracle as cloud evangelist and today I'm
Oracle作为云技术的传播者，今天我
going to talk to you about
要和你谈谈
we are micro service with Java EE well
我们是Java EE的微服务提供商
micro service is one of the most
微服务是最热门的服务之一
important buzzwords that we have in the
我们在其中使用的重要流行语
software industry and not surprising
软件行业并不奇怪
because many big companies many big
因为很多大公司很多
projects are using it today so what
项目今天正在使用它，那又如何
about Java is it possible to build micro
关于Java是否有可能构建微型
service real macro service with Java of
使用Java的服务真正的宏服务
course it is and I'm going to show you
当然是，我将向您展示
right now it's a simple demo here I'm
现在这是一个简单的演示
showing a lot of cold well I have here
我在这里表现得很冷
example of a monolith built in with Java
用Java内置的整体示例
and then I'm gonna show you how to broke
然后我要告诉你如何打破
the monolith into micro service so
整体式微服务
basically what I'm doing here it's a
基本上我在这里做的是
simple example playing with player and
与播放器一起玩的简单示例
ranked like a gaming or so so you have
像游戏一样排名，所以你有
here an entity that is our player ok you
在这里，一个实体是我们的玩家，好的
think about GPA a database and so on so
考虑GPA，数据库等等
we have here an entity that is a player
我们这里有一个实体，是一个玩家
and we have also another entity that is
我们还有另一个实体
our player rank another entity that's
我们的玩家将另一个实体
related to our player we have here the
与我们的球员有关，我们在这里
relation with the player ok this is will
与玩家的关系确定，这将是
be important when we are breaking down
当我们崩溃时很重要
into macro service and we also have our
进入宏服务，我们也有我们的
beings that will make the manipulation
可以操纵的生物
of their data with player as we have
他们与球员的数据
done also with JPA so we can save player
也可以通过JPA完成，因此我们可以节省播放器
and move player find by ID final and we
并通过ID最终将玩家找到，我们
have the same for a sorry for rank so
对等级感到遗憾
you have here another state lisbon that
你在这里有另一个州立里斯本
we also save remove find by ID and find
我们还保存通过ID删除查找并查找
all and here we bought we build some
全部，我们在这里购买，我们建造了一些
some service so ninety point service
一些服务，所以九十点服务
rest and point serves for
休息和服务点
actually find BIID add new save remove
实际找到BIID添加新保存删除
the same with the same stuff that we've
与我们拥有的相同的东西
done with the daystate last service all
使用daystate最后一次服务全部完成
right and here we have for our player
对的，这里有我们的球员
rank okay so what I've done here also
排名还可以，所以我在这里也做了
for our our mono leaf is wrote several
因为我们的单叶写了几首
gene unit tests here so we can try if
基因单元测试在这里，所以我们可以尝试
those do stuff very working so we can
那些确实很有效，所以我们可以
try it right now and we'll use basically
立即尝试，我们将基本上使用
the same stuff that that we've done
我们所做的相同的事情
before in this series with JPA
在本系列的JPA之前
where we created a test for running our
我们在其中创建了用于运行我们的测试的测试
GPA access to database and try out those
GPA访问数据库并尝试那些
methods for JP okay so it's built the
JP的方法还可以，因此建立了
taste the text really successfully so
品尝文字真的很成功，所以
this is our monolith doing with javi so
这是我们与哈维做的巨石，所以
how do we now can take those monolith
我们现在该如何拿走那些巨石
and break it down tube macro service
并分解它的宏服务
because we have here the player and a
因为我们这里有玩家和一个
player ranked let's split this monofin
玩家排名让我们来拆分这个单鳍
to processing through projects into
通过项目加工成
artifacts so we can have kind of micro
文物，所以我们可以有一种微
services here so first of all we have
服务在这里，所以首先
just splitted in true projects basically
基本上只是拆分成真实的项目
have the same same files a key here on
具有相同的文件
the the on this project on the macro
该项目在宏上
service player and we have on the
服务玩家，我们在
specific case of the player we didn't
我们没有的球员的具体情况
have any change at all is except for
根本没有任何变化，除了
there is no rank in the project so if we
这个项目没有等级，所以如果我们
have here the the beam is almost the
光束几乎在这里
same the same beam and and if we have
相同的光束，如果我们有
here the service during the point is
这里的服务是
also the same didn't change at all
同样一点都没有改变
so the project for play didn't change so
所以玩的项目没有改变
much for the rank we had yes some
我们的排名很多
changes because as I said before there
变化，因为正如我之前所说
were the relation between the rank
等级之间的关系
and the player so what I've done here is
和玩家，所以我在这里所做的是
that there is as we don't have player
因为我们没有玩家
anymore inside the project and when we
在项目内部以及当我们
are doing microservice we usually and is
我们通常在做微服务
the best practice that each service has
每个服务具有的最佳实践
its own database so in this case we are
它自己的数据库，所以在这种情况下，我们是
changing the player relationship forges
改变玩家关系的伪造
player ID so we have changed here for a
玩家ID，因此我们在此处更改了
long stead of the specifically player
长期以来专门的球员
object so we are just storing the player
对象，所以我们只是存储播放器
ID and the database for rank and then
ID和数据库的等级，然后
you it will go up to the application
您将转到应用程序
should do the relationship or if you
应该做的关系，或者如果你
have some reports to take after that it
之后要有一些报告
will be up to the reports to do that
将取决于报告来做到这一点
relationship their logical relationship
关系他们的逻辑关系
because each data each macro service has
因为每个宏服务具有的每个数据
to hold its own database okay so that's
可以保存自己的数据库，所以
why we channel here and that's what
为什么我们在这里引导，这就是
basically the most changes okay so when
基本上变化最大，所以当
you have the the endpoint service didn't
您有终结点服务没有
say that much well but just splitting
说的很好，但只是分裂
the the project into two pieces isn't
该项目分为两部分不是
enough okay that's not enough to have
足够好，那还不够
the real macro service what approach
真正的宏服务采用什么方法
that we use it here is Xu is called API
我们在这里使用它的徐称为API
gateway okay so we just built a gateway
网关好，所以我们刚刚建立了一个网关
to deal with those both macro service so
处理那些既宏服务
we have here a player gateway that will
我们这里有一个播放器网关
hope that this the the the communication
希望这次的交流
between your client okay okay can be a
您的客户之间好吧好吧可以是
mobile client a web client the desktop
移动客户端Web客户端桌面
client whatever clients do you have it
客户无论您拥有什么客户
the Gateway will be inside the middle of
网关将位于
communication between your macro service
您的宏服务之间的通信
in your client so here we have another
在您的客户中，所以在这里我们还有另一个
endpoint that will build a client a web
将建立客户网络的端点
client web target and you just pointing
客户网络目标，而您只是指向
to to your macro service player
到您的宏服务播放器
and here communicate with the same
在这里与同一个人沟通
endpoint that we have on the player on
我们在播放器上拥有的端点
the micro-service player the end point
微服务播放器的终点
for them so find buy ad find all and
为他们找到买广告找到所有和
player service for save and for removing
播放器服务，用于保存和删除
so here we have the possibility to have
所以在这里我们有可能
all the deception dealing all the the
所有的欺骗处理
the any specific activity or management
任何特定的活动或管理
that you need to to have if from macro
从宏中需要的
cells you can do in this gateway and we
您可以在此网关中完成的单元
have also a endpoint gateway for your
还有一个端点网关
your rank in the same the same way that
您的排名以相同的方式
we've done on the player so we have here
我们已经在播放器上完成了，所以我们在这里
building a client and here doing the
建立客户，然后在这里做
communication with your your endpoint
与您的端点通信
that is in the macro service the the
在宏服务中
good part flow from the gateway is that
来自网关的良好部分流程是
you can use it for example if your
例如，如果您的
Microsoft's change the the place didn't
微软改变的地方没有
yes the address or change technology
是的，地址或更改技术
change Porsche or change anything that
改变保时捷或改变任何东西
the the contract between the the api's
api之间的合同
you can keep your gateways to and touch
您可以保持访问并触摸
it for your client perspective but your
从您的客户角度来看，但您的
micro source perspective you can change
您可以更改的微源视角
a lot and without break any relationship
很多不间断的任何关系
with your clients you can also even
与您的客户甚至
change the technology if you're using
如果您正在使用，请更改技术
Java and you you're gonna use Python or
Java，您将使用Python或
gonna use anything you can use the
将使用任何您可以使用的
Gateway to to decrease the the break
减少中断的网关
that you could cows to reach your
你可以牛到达你的
clients so it's very good and it's one
客户，这非常好，这是一个
approach okay
可以
but that's what we use here so we get a
但这就是我们在这里使用的，所以我们得到了
monolith in you will break in broken
你里面的巨石会破碎
into projects to macro service and you
进入宏服务项目，您
created a new service that is our
创建了一项新服务
gateway to communicate between them and
他们之间进行通信的网关
if we have another micro service another
如果我们还有另一个微服务
application that we built in our
我们内置的应用程序
application we just put it inside of our
应用程序，我们只是将其放在我们的内部
gateway and your clutch this access your
网关和您的离合器访问您的
gateway and you are very very of
网关，您非常非常
flexible to give another features new
灵活提供其他新功能
features to your clients okay so as you
向您的客户推荐功能还可以
saw is quite simple to take your heavy
锯很简单
application they break down into Micro
应用细分为Micro
sirs actually isn't just break down the
先生实际上不只是分解了
whole code you need us actually the
整个代码，您实际上需要我们
environment you need some service
环境需要一些服务
discovery service registry but for for
发现服务注册表，但用于
coding perspective it's a way to get
编码角度来看，这是一种获取方法
started and hope you enjoy it and also I
开始，希望你喜欢它，我也
hope you enjoy the whole series I find
希望您喜欢我发现的整个系列
is helpful and thank you very much
是有帮助的，非常感谢